<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.10.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2024-12-08T13:42:13+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Travis Yip</title><entry><title type="html">London Heathrow Airport Operation – A Tableau Dashboard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/heathrow_ops_dashboard/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="London Heathrow Airport Operation – A Tableau Dashboard" /><published>2024-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2024-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/heathrow_ops_dashboard</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/heathrow_ops_dashboard/"><![CDATA[<div>
<div class="tableauPlaceholder" id="viz1713564621090" style="position: relative">
<noscript>
    <a href="#"><img alt="Dashboard 1 " src="https:&#47;&#47;public.tableau.com&#47;static&#47;images&#47;Lo&#47;LondonHeathrowTrafficFlow-17April2024&#47;Dashboard1&#47;1_rss.png" style="border: none" />
    </a>
</noscript>

<object class="tableauViz" style="display:none;"><param name="host_url" value="https%3A%2F%2Fpublic.tableau.com%2F" /> <param name="embed_code_version" value="3" /> <param name="site_root" value="" /><param name="name" value="LondonHeathrowTrafficFlow-17April2024&#47;Dashboard1" /><param name="tabs" value="no" /><param name="toolbar" value="yes" /><param name="static_image" value="https:&#47;&#47;public.tableau.com&#47;static&#47;images&#47;Lo&#47;LondonHeathrowTrafficFlow-17April2024&#47;Dashboard1&#47;1.png" /> <param name="animate_transition" value="yes" /><param name="display_static_image" value="yes" /><param name="display_spinner" value="yes" /><param name="display_overlay" value="yes" /><param name="display_count" value="yes" /><param name="language" value="en-GB" />
</object>

</div>                
<script type="text/javascript">                    var divElement = document.getElementById('viz1713564621090');                    var vizElement = divElement.getElementsByTagName('object')[0];                    if ( divElement.offsetWidth > 800 ) { vizElement.style.width='1000px';vizElement.style.height='827px';} else if ( divElement.offsetWidth > 500 ) { vizElement.style.width='1000px';vizElement.style.height='827px';} else { vizElement.style.width='100%';vizElement.style.height='1827px';}                     var scriptElement = document.createElement('script');                    scriptElement.src = 'https://public.tableau.com/javascripts/api/viz_v1.js';                    vizElement.parentNode.insertBefore(scriptElement, vizElement);                
</script>
</div>

<p>On 17 April 2024, there are 1341 scheduled commercial flights at London Health Airport (LHR), connecting passengers to over 179 destinations.</p>

<p>While there are some variations in the number of departing and arriving flights, they are by and large equivalent. Each aircraft is likely to turn around within the same day, constrained by the number of aircraft stands.</p>

<p>In total, there were 23 cancellations, out of which 10 flights were scheduled to operate between Heathrow and Western Asia, including the UAE. These cancellations are likely due to the extreme weather event in the area.</p>

<p>Most flights between London Heathrow were short-haul, with travel departing to/arriving from Europe. Over 40% of the flights were connected to destinations within the region. However, the US was the country with the most connections to Heathrow, contributing to over 260,000 daily passengers to Heathrow.</p>

<p>Over two-thirds of the flights were delayed. Among arrivals, the delay rate was 36%. On the contrary, almost all departure flights were delayed with an average delay time of 40 minutes. All of the 15 flights departing for Eastern Asia were delayed by an average of over an hour.</p>

<p><span style="color:#8F8F8F"><em>Author’s Note:<br />The passenger number is simulated data. The number of passengers for each flight is assumed to be normally distributed at a mean of 200 and a standard deviation of 75. Since the passenger number is determined by the flight, passengers who were transiting through the airport with onward journey are double counted.</em></span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dataViz" /><category term="Tableau" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Food Poverty in London in 2023</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/trussle_trust_2021_23/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food Poverty in London in 2023" /><published>2024-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-02-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/trussle_trust_2021_23</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/trussle_trust_2021_23/"><![CDATA[<div style="position: relative; width: 90%; padding-bottom: 60%;margin: 0 auto;">
  <iframe src="/asset/trussell_trust_2021_23.html" style="position: absolute; width: 100%; height: 100%;" frameborder="0">
  </iframe>
</div>

<p>This visualisation shows the the number of emergency food parcels Trussell Trust delivered over the the given financial years.
While the Trust has made their data available across all local authorities in the UK, including Northern Ireland, Scotland, and Wales,
these data points were not included in this exploratory analysis due to the constraint of computational power.
Data from 2021 and 2022 is also removed from the interactive plot due to the storage contraint of the server.</p>

<p>While Trussel Trust is one of the major charity providing food to the population at risk of food poverty,
the data explored in this graph may not be representative. 
Firstly, this data only includes food parcels distributed by Trussell Trust. 
Delivery by other independent food banks were not included.
Secondly, there could be significant spillover effect whereby the recipient of the
emergency food parcels may collect the proceeding at a location away from their shelter or home.
Therefore, the aggregates at the borough should be taken with consideration.</p>

<p>The raw data is obtained through the <a href="https://www.trusselltrust.org/wp-content/uploads/sites/2/2023/04/Trussell-Trust-End-of-Year-Statistics-2022-23.xlsx">download link</a>. 
Trussel Trust also published their analysis on the data on the <a href="https://www.trusselltrust.org/news-and-blog/latest-stats/end-year-stats/">End of Year Stats</a> page.</p>

<p><span style="color:#8F8F8F"><em>Author’s Note:<br />Detailed methodology for the data management process is yet to be published.</em></span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="interactive" /><category term="dataViz" /><category term="foodPoverty" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Regional GDP in England and Wales</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/eng_wales_regional_gdp/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Regional GDP in England and Wales" /><published>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/eng_wales_regional_gdp</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/eng_wales_regional_gdp/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/20240122_gdp_by_region_02.png" alt="Absolute GDP in 2019 million pounds" />
The latest <a href="https://www.ons.gov.uk/economy/grossdomesticproductgdp/methodologies/grossdomesticproductgdpukregionsandcountriesqmi">GDP index</a> published by the ONS shows that England and Wales generated close to 500 billion in 2019 pounds. London alone contributes to 27% of the economic output in the region.</p>

<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/20240122_gdp_gr_by_region_01.png" alt="Latest Quarter GDP (Value-Added) by Industry" />
Compared to the previous year, London’s economy fared better compared to the rest of England and Wales in the recovery from COVID-19. Comparing the third quarterly GDP between 2022 and 2023, the economy has grown and rebounded by over 6%, more than double the country’s aggregated. According to a <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Ype43hG6lN8&amp;t=620s">TLDR; report</a>, this discrepancy is attributed to regional inequality: The wealthier region is more resilient and emerges from the economic turmoil better than those on the other end of the spectrum.</p>

<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/20240122_gdp_gr_by_region_04.png" alt="GDP Growth Rate by Industry" />
Looking at the GDP growth rate aggregated by industry, it seems that this recovery is also in part due to the strong growth that is seen in the servicing sector. In fact, the 8% growth in the GDP generated from the service industry offset the decrease in GDP generated from both the production (–13%) and construction industry (–8%) in 2023.</p>

<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/20240122_gdp_wgr_by_region_03.png" alt="Weighted GDP Growth Rate by Industry" />
This outsized effect of the service industry on the overall regional economic growth is due to the major role the industry has on London’s economy at baseline. Adjusted for the importance of the industry to the region’s economy, the service sector contributed 7.57% point to the total GDP growth in the period. More interestingly, it also shows that the decrease in economic output from the production and manufacturing industry took a bigger toll on the GDP growth in the rest of England and Wales. After adjusting for the industry’s weight on the aggregate GDP growth rate, the manufacturing and production industry pulled back the regional economic growth in the rest of England and Wales three times compared to that in London.</p>

<p><span style="color:#8F8F8F"><em>Author’s Note:<br />In this analysis, we have ignored the hit of COVID-19 on the GDP by sector. This should be addressed in the next revision of the analysis. Due to the constraint of data availability, quarterly GDP data is used and compared to the same quarter across different years to minimise the distortion of seasonability of the analysis of the data. We also only focused on Wales and England and ignored Scotland and Northern Ireland due to data availability constraints. The GDP index is converted into 2019 monetary value using the <a href="https://www.ons.gov.uk/file?uri=/economy/grossvalueaddedgva/datasets/nominalandrealregionalgrossvalueaddedbalancedbyindustry/current/regionalgrossvalueaddedbalancedbyindustryandallitlregions.xlsx">GDP dataset</a>. For detailed methodology, this could found in the respective <a href="https://github.com/cwtravisyip/ONS_Census2021">GitHub repository</a>.</em></span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dataViz" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The latest GDP index published by the ONS shows that England and Wales generated close to 500 billion in 2019 pounds. London alone contributes to 27% of the economic output in the region.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Food Desert Prediction</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/food_desert/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Food Desert Prediction" /><published>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/food_desert</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/food_desert/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/240113food_desert_map.png" alt="Food Desert Distribution" /></p>

<p>Commonly known as food deserts, <em>Low-Income and Low-Access Tracts</em> are defined by the US Department of Agriculture as census tracts “<a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/food-access-research-atlas/download-the-data/">characterised by at least 500 people and/or 33% of the tract population residing more than 1 mile from a supermarket or large grocery in urban areas, and more than 10 miles in rural area</a>”. Due to the lack of access to healthy foods, food desert residents are exposed to a higher risk of chronic diseases. Coupled with the income status residents often find themselves in, it creates a vicious cycle that <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Rd8J-9uUnfc">traps residents in a poverty cycle</a>.</p>

<p>The USDA has conducted three series of <a href="https://www.ers.usda.gov/data-products/food-access-research-atlas/">Food Access Research Atlas</a> since 2006. As detailed in the documentation, the classification of census tracts into food deserts or not requires a series of census data and a complete list of fully operational food outlets that represent sources of affordable and nutritious food. However, the exact methodology has not been published. Given the data source employed, however, one could reasonably guess that sptial analysis was employed where each household is mapped to its closest food outlet and the distance is computed using conventional GIS programmes. This is of course a lengthy process and the reliability of the food outlet data could be questioned, particularly after the COVID-19 pandemic.</p>

<p>This is where the machine learning methods may come into play. The American Community Survey provides an ongoing data source that enables more time-sensitive estimation of the location of food deserts. Using a myriad of social-demographic data and geospatial data, there is a potential to derive patterns for identifying food deserts.  Naturally, these machine learning models should take into account income level and spatial data of some sort. One natural contender would be the area of the census tract.</p>

<p>Using a simple decision tree algorithm where the census tract is segmented into two groups by iteratively evaluating them using a set of true or false questions, we yielded a model that can correctly classify 33% of previously unseen food deserts. No doubt, this result shows that the machine learning methods are not up for the task. Using a more complex model, such as a random forest does not improve the performance either.</p>

<p>Nonetheless, the result from the decision tree shows that income and census tract size are the two most important features to consider when predicting the prevalence of food deserts. Moving forward, we may consider including other social-demographic variables and consider different ways to engineer features that provide better input and proxies that help segregate food deserts from non-food deserts.</p>

<p><span style="color:#8F8F8F"><em>Author’s Note:<br />For detailed methodologies for data acquisition, manipulation and the training of machine learning models, you can visit the respective <a href="https://github.com/cwtravisyip/USDA_food_desert">GitHub Repository</a>.</em></span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dataViz" /><category term="geospatial" /><category term="machineLearning" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hurdle to Paris’ Sustainable Future</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/paris_building_age/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hurdle to Paris’ Sustainable Future" /><published>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-01-15T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/portfolio/paris_building_age</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/portfolio/paris_building_age/"><![CDATA[<p><img src="/images/porfolio_of_work/240113building_age.png" alt="Building by Construction Pperiod" /></p>

<p>Since the pandemic and the years leading up to the 2024 Olympics, the city of Paris has been in the quest to rebrand itself as a sustainable city in line with <a href="https://sdgs.un.org/goals/goal11">the UN’s Sustainable Development Goal 11: Sustainable cities and communities</a>. While cities around the world are still recovering from the economic crisis brought about by the COVID-19 Pandemic, Paris has taken advantage of the time to reimagine its city landscape and transform itself into a <a href="https://bigthink.com/strange-maps/15-minute-city-paris/">15-minute city</a>. However, challenges remain, particularly, in reducing its energy footprint.</p>

<p>In 2019, it was recorded that heating contributes to <a href="https://www.apur.org/fr/nos-travaux/consommation-energie-habitants-grand-paris#:~:text=En%202019%2C%20la%20consommation%20énergétique,6%20000%20kWh%20par%20an">63% of the city’s total energy consumption</a>. This poses a huge opportunity for the city looking to reduce its energy bill for the environment, not to mention the energy crisis the country found itself in at the beginning of 2022. This could be done by reducing the absolute energy consumption and by improving the energy efficiency.</p>

<p>According to <a href="https://geoweb.iau-idf.fr/webapps/energif/?x=2.3345409633301695&amp;y=48.90247581907779&amp;zoom=9&amp;id_appli=conso">Energif</a>, retrofitting existing buildings could save the city 24% of its energy. This process is of course not a small feat. A lot of the buildings characterising Paris have a long history that dates back to the Hauseman Renovation in the 19th century or earlier, but so are the building technologies. More than <a href="https://opendata.apur.org/datasets/Apur::emprise-batie-paris/about">three-fourths of the buildings</a> that scatter around the city were built before the first building insulation regulation was introduced in France.</p>

<p>The city <a href="https://www.weforum.org/agenda/2021/10/paris-plans-completely-cyclable-by-2026/">has turned its road infrastructure into a labyrinth of cycle lanes</a> when people are locked away from home. What would it take for the city to foot the bill to improve its buildings’ energy footprint?</p>

<p><span style="color:#8F8F8F"><em>Author’s Note:<br />For detailed methodologies of the production of the map, including the data source and manipulation, you can visit the respective <a href="https://github.com/cwtravisyip/paris_urban_data_visualisation">GitHub Repository</a> for details.</em></span></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="dataViz" /><category term="geospatial" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry></feed>